memoq.com 2018-03-17

# Kilgray Privacy policy

##### This Privacy Policy was updated on April 1, 2016

* * *

This Privacy Policy applies 

  * when you visit, browse, and/or register on any website under memoq.com, kilgray.com, or languageterminal.com.
  * when you use memoQ, memoQ server, memoQ cloud server, memoQweb, QTerm, or any products or services provided by Kilgray.
  * when you contact Kilgray for customer support.

Kilgray is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal and stored information. Amendments to this Privacy Policy will be posted at this URL and will be effective when posted.

By using any website or product provided by Kilgray, you provide your consent to the collection and use of your personal and stored information in the manner described below.

By continuing to use any websites or products provided by Kilgray after an amendment was posted, you accept that amendment, modification, or change.

The memoQ translation environment, memoQ server, memoQ cloud server, memoQweb, Qterm, memoQ support, and Language Terminal are all provided by Kilgray Translation Technologies Ltd. Any of these terms in the Privacy Policy refer to Kilgray Ltd. as a legal entity.  
Products and services that use the name memoQ but do not refer to memoQ the translation enviroment do not belong to Kilgray Ltd. Kilgray Ltd. will not accept liability for any activities of other organizations that use a synonymous name but are not related to the above products and services.

This Privacy Policy is governed by Hungarian law and EU legal standards, particularly by the Hungarian Personal Data Protection Code that governs the processing of personal data. Furthermore, recognizing the global nature of the internet, you agree to comply with all local laws including, without limitation, laws about the Internet, data, email, or privacy. Specifically, you agree to comply with all applicable laws and concerning the transmission of technical data exported from the country in which you reside.

If you enter into a business relationship with Kilgray, and you are billed for products or services, your personal and billing details as well as the records of your purchases must be kept on accounting records for no fewer than eight (8) years after your last purchase, as is mandated by Hungarian tax regulations.

The following sections provide specific information on data collected and used in various products and online services provided by Kilgray. 

* * *

####   
**1- Personal information on memoq.com and related websites**

When you visit a website on memoq.com or kilgray.com, or you visit any affiliated sites and services, you may be asked to identify yourself and specify personal information before you can access information, request a trial, ask for support, or receive licenses.  
Kilgray will never disclose personal information to third parties without your express permission.

Kilgray may use personal details to send direct communication, including a regular newsletter, from which you can opt out.

Kilgray makes all effort to protect personal details from unauthorized access.

memoq.com websites will use tracking cookies to record your browsing habits and display advertisements accordingly. Kilgray does not use these cookies to identify you, and you may block these or use the private mode of your Web browser. You will not be prevented from browsing the site if you do that. 

* * *

####   
**2-  memoQ**

memoQ may collect your name, company name, e-mail address, phone number, and product serial number before you are allowed to use your licenses. If you do not agree to specify these details to Kilgray, you may not use memoQ. When you are asking for a serial number for the first time, memoQ will send these details to Kilgray’s central activation server, and they will be added to Kilgray’s records.

The main identifier of your copy of memoQ is your serial number. Using the serial number, Kilgray is able to retrieve your personal details from its records.

On startup, memoQ will send usage information to Kilgray. This usage information includes the product version you are using, the user interface language, and the country. No personal details are sent.

To access various enhanced services available for memoQ users, you can connect memoQ to Language Terminal by specifying your Language Terminal user name and password to memoQ. memoQ will not send information about this to Kilgray. Language Terminal will track this information to provide statistics, and Kilgray may access this information to provide tailored services and offers. However, Kilgray will not access actual data you work with, and Kilgray will not forward any of this information to third parties.

When a general error occurs in memoQ, you may prompt memoQ to send troubleshooting information to memoQ support. When memoQ collects and sends this information, it may send on contents of your work (that might be sensitive information according to your client). The transmission is encoded and encrypted, so that unauthorized access to the contents is very difficult. Kilgray will treat the data according to the rules of memoQ support (see next section).

* * *

####   
**3- memoQ support**

memoQ support does not provide assistance in an anonymous manner. Users requesting assistance must identify themselves and provide proof of either a valid memoQ or memoQ server license, an active trial period, or a valid memoQ cloud server subscription.

To diagnose a specific problem, memoQ support may require that you send additional details, including documents, resources (translation memories, term bases etc.) or other content. Kilgray recognizes that these items may contain sensitive information, and will treat them as such.

Kilgray will not disclose such documents and resources to third parties, except for the development companies that work with Kilgray on a regular contract basis. Kilgray may retain the documents and resources in the issue tracking databases as long as this is necessary to resolve and follow up on related problems.

Both the memoQ support database and the issue tracking system is available to authorized customer support and development personnel only, and they are protected from unauthorized access.

A customer may access all past and pending issues they have submitted. A customer may not access issues submitted by other customers. Before you can access your issues, you need to register and identify yourself to the memoQ support site.

Customer support issues that belong to an organization (that is a customer) may be visible to all authorized personnel from that organization. Please contact memoQ support if you wish to review the circle of authorized staff.

* * *

####   
**4-  memoQ server**

memoQ server is a software product offered by Kilgray that provides for collaborative translation by sharing resources and managing translation projects. memoQ server is licensed software, and is usually installed on a server computer owned or at least operated by the customer and not Kilgray.

A memoQ server might be operated by Kilgray in two cases: 

  1. The customer subscribes to a memoQ cloud server, or
  2. The customer orders hosting services from Kilgray, so that they do not have to operate their memoQ server in their own infrastructure.

For more information, see the sections on memoQ cloud server and hosted memoQ servers.

If you use memoQ, memoQweb, or QTerm to access a memoQ server, you must use a user name and password that is valid on the memoQ server in question. Your personal details will not be transmitted, but the memoQ server may have some of them on record.

A memoQ server is not connected to Kilgray’s central databases in any manner, except for the activation server to validate its own licenses. A memoQ server will not forward user information to Kilgray.

Your user account on a memoQ server is not connected to your details stored in Kilgray’s central databases in any manner. Kilgray will not make this connection even when they operate the server, no matter whether the server is a memoQ cloud server or a licensed server hosted by Kilgray.

A memoQ server can connect to Language Terminal, so that users can log on to it using their Language Terminal user names and passwords. Kilgray will not track such server usage.

* * *

####   
**5-  Language Terminal**

Language Terminal (languageterminal.com) is an open translation management service portal provided by Kilgray, where you can build up your professional profile, and access various services that work with data that you upload to the portal.

Everyone has the right to protect their personal data and profile. Your profile and your data are yours – and you can make your profile unavailable to others. Language Terminal respects the right of its users to be informed about the collection of and other operations involving their personal data. Kilgray will only use or manage data that may directly or indirectly identify you personally when it is absolutely necessary to provide assistance or prevent data loss.

You can make your profile available for searching. If you do this, other users of Language Terminal can view your profile details, but not the files you uploaded and store under your profile.

It is not possible to access  Language Terminal anonymously. Anyone who wants to view or otherwise access data on Language Terminal needs to log in as a member. Before users can create an account, they must specify, confirm, and verify their e-mail addresses.  
Language Terminal creates aggregate reports from user data, which are available to Kilgray.

Kilgray does not allow third parties to access your details and data in any manner. An exception is when Language Terminal members share their details with each other, but even then you decide about sharing your details and/or data.

Access to Language Terminal is always encrypted. Kilgray makes all possible effort to protect user data from unauthorized access or modification. This includes the proper intrusion protection of our servers running Language Terminal. We will take reasonable care to maintain appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the information you have entered in Language Terminal.  
Details and data of different Language Terminal users are isolated from each other. No profile data can be accessed without proper prior authentication and authorization, unless you make your details public. Your details are not publicly available by default.

Language Terminal may collect non-personally identifiable information about you in a number of ways, including tracking your activities through IP address, computer settings or the most-recently visited URLs. Language Terminal may also ask you to provide certain non-personally identifiable information about yourself such as your preferences, etc. Language Terminal does not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you voluntarily submit such information to us, by, for example, filling out a survey or registration from.

If you subscribe to the translation memory and term base sharing service, Kilgray reserves the right to mine your data to improve their products in different language pairs. Entire segments or confidential information will not be disclosed to third parties, or included in the product. If you do not agree to this, do not use the translation memory or term base sharing service, but rather consider subscribing to a memoQ cloud server with one project manager license, where Kilgray will not analyze your data.

Language Terminal currently runs on servers hosted in Germany.

* * *

####   
**6- memoQ cloud server**

memoQ cloud server is a Software as a Service (SaaS) solution offered by Kilgray. A memoQ cloud server is one running instance of the memoQ server software, owned and operated by Kilgray, for your exclusive use and benefit.

You can access the memoQ cloud server by subscribing to it. When you subscribe, you will be required to identify yourself, and provide payment information to Kilgray so that your subscription fee can be collected.

Kilgray is using a third-party certified payment provider. Your payment details are not given to or stored in any of Kilgray’s systems, and your subscription is available to you and you alone, except for Kilgray personnel who are required to provide assistance when necessary.  
All data that you enter, create, import, or add to your memoQ cloud server are exclusively owned by you. Kilgray will make all effort to protect your data from unauthorized access.

Kilgray will not allow third parties – not even unauthorized members of your organization – to access your memoQ cloud server, except at your explicit request.

Kilgray will not copy, publish, or otherwise make available the data to third parties, with the exception of creating backup copies for your exclusive benefit and for the purpose of disaster recovery.

Kilgray will not access or analyze your data with the sole exception of mission-critical troubleshooting or disaster recovery, and even then, Kilgray will do so only at your express request. This is different from the protection of the translation memories and term bases you upload to Language Terminal, where Kilgray reserves the right to analyze the data you upload, with the purpose of linguistic research.

Kilgray may make up to two copies of the data on their premises or on the storage space offered by the data center for the purpose of backup. Kilgray will make all effort to prevent third parties and unauthorized personnel from accessing these copies.

You may download a copy of the data through the memoQ page of the My Account pages on the memoq.com portal.  
Computers that host memoQ cloud servers currently run in Germany.

* * *

#### **7- Hosted memoQ servers**

A hosted memoQ server is a memoQ server where your organization owns the server license and controls memoQ server, but the server computer is operated by Kilgray.

Authorized Kilgray personnel always have administrative access to a hosted server; this is a prerequisite of providing the service. You may request administrative access for your organization; however, in that case, Kilgray will no longer be responsible for the privacy and the integrity of data on that server.

Kilgray will not allow third parties – not even unauthorized members of your organization – to access your hosted memoQ server, except at your explicit request.

All data that you enter, create, import, or add to your hosted memoQ server are exclusively owned by you. Kilgray will make all effort to protect your data from unauthorized access.

Kilgray willl not copy, publish, or otherwise make available the data to third parties, with the exception of creating backup copies for your exclusive benefit and for the purpose of disaster recovery.

Kilgray will not access or analyze your data with the sole exception of mission-critical troubleshooting or disaster recovery, and even then, Kilgray will do so only at your express written request.

Kilgray may make up to two copies of the data on their premises or on the storage space offered by the data center for the purpose of backup. Kilgray will make all effort to prevent third parties and unauthorized personnel from accessing these copies.

Kilgray will make the backups available to you at your express request. Normally, the backups are stored in a reasonably isolated system, so that the risk of unauthorized access is kept to a minimum.

Hosted memoQ servers run in Germany, France, and the USA. You can choose from these countries when ordering the service. 

* * *

####   
**8- memoQfest conference**

memoQfest is the only regular public event organized by Kilgray.

To register for memoQfest, you need to specify personal, billing, and payment information at the memoq.com website. Kilgray will store and process this information exclusively for the purpose of the memoQfest conference.

Your details will not be forwarded to anyone except authorized Kilgray personnel who need to bill your registration and prepare the conference.

Your details will not be included in the list of participants unless you explicitly say so in a survey that Kilgray sends you shortly before the conference.

On the other hand, Kilgray will have your details on file and may send you newsletters and other communication, from which you may opt out.

* * *

#### **9- memoQ e-learning site**

The memoQ e-learning site is available at elearning.memoq.com, and is operated by the Moodle system.

To enroll in the courses available from the memoQ e-learning site, you need to log in using your Kilgray (Language Terminal) account.

The memoQ e-learning site uses your e-mail address to send you messages about your progress, and also about your exam results. Once you enroll in a course, it is no longer possible to opt out of these e-mail notifications. The e-learning site will not use your e-mail address for any other purpose. However, since this is the same e-mail address that you use with other Kilgray sites and services, you may receive e-mails from the other sites even if you do not enroll to a course.

Your progress and exam results are not visible to other students in the system, but they are visible to Kilgray personnel operating the e-learning system.

The e-learning system may allow you to start discussions, post topics as well as blog entries. These posts will be visible to other students in the system, and they may also be visible to the public.

####  **10   Servers not operated by Kilgray**

If your organization owns a memoQ server license, and the server computer is operated by you, protecting sensitive data is your responsibility. You are entitled to advice from Kilgray about safeguarding data on the server, but Kilgray will not be liable for any breaches on a computer they do not control.

If you use memoQ or memoQweb to connect to a memoQ server that is not operated by Kilgray, the privacy and security of data on that server is the responsibility of the server’s owner and not of Kilgray. Kilgray will not be liable for any breaches on computers they do not control.

Any website or online service that does not run under one of the following domains: 

  * memoq.com,
  * kilgray.com,
  * languageterminal.com,
  * memoqworld.com,

is not affiliated with Kilgray, and Kilgray will not be liable for any privacy issues on those websites or online services.

* * *

To download a .pdf version of this Privavy Policy, click here.
